<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-13T16:11:38-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Pacific Crest Trail</title><subtitle>My trail journal while I hike the Pacific Crest Trail, northbound, in 2017</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The End</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/12/The-End/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The End" /><published>2017-09-12T23:42:38-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-12T23:42:38-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/12/The-End</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/12/The-End/">&lt;p&gt;I tried to sleep in today, but it felt like Christmas. All night long I thought about finishing the trail. When morning finally came I got up and started hiking. The guys I was with were meeting one of their girlfriends at the border a little later so I hiked on alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/The EndPost0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiking today was surreal. It was a perfect day with amazing views. The last 14 miles are some of the best on the whole trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw a guy I shared a hotel room with way back in Southern California. He had finished the day before and was hiking back to Hart’s Pass. We talked for awhile about how crazy this hike has been. Then I hiked on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/The EndPost1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved this sign. It’s such an American thing to do to make a sign saying we’re heading to the US border, when we’re in the US. It’s not incorrect to say I started and finished at he US border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before noon, I arrived at the northern terminus of the PCT. It came faster than I thought it would and I had it all to myself. I didn’t cry. I didn’t yell. I was just happy. Four months of hiking was over. I accomplished my goal. It was an amazing feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/The EndPost2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not too long later a woman showed up from the Canadian side. She was waiting for Bubba and Lunch to finish. I told her I had been hiking with them and they should be there soon. She took my picture and we talked while I ate lunch. Everyone showed up and we celebrated at the monument. We shared stories and then hiked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s another 8 miles from the border to Manning Park. It went by fast. What’s 8 miles after you’ve done 2650? At the resort I got some food and checked into my hotel room. I went to the pool and hung out for a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finishing something like this is incredible. As I look back at what I had to go through, I can’t believe I did it. Thank you to everyone that helped me along the way. The packages, the places to stay, the rides, and the support of everyone made this possible. Walking was the easy part.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Randall</name></author><summary type="html">I tried to sleep in today, but it felt like Christmas. All night long I thought about finishing the trail. When morning finally came I got up and started hiking. The guys I was with were meeting one of their girlfriends at the border a little later so I hiked on alone.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Last Night On Trail</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/11/The-Last-Night-On-Trail/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Last Night On Trail" /><published>2017-09-11T19:25:38-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-11T19:25:38-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/11/The-Last-Night-On-Trail</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/11/The-Last-Night-On-Trail/">&lt;p&gt;The first thing I do when I decide to get up in the morning is open the valve on my air mattress. This forces me to get up. Today, when I pulled in the valve, it came all the way off. Well, at least it lasted me almost exactly one thru-hike. I was able to get the valve back on so it holds air for tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/The Last Night On TrailPost0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather today was perfect. Clear blue skies and cool temperatures that were perfect for hiking. Just before lunch, I made it to Hart’s Pass, the last road before Canada. This was the last possible place for the trail to be closed so making it past there made me ecstatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to hike slower today and take more breaks. I really wanted to enjoy the last day. I passed a lot of people going south. Some flipped to the border so they could beat snow in the North Cascades, others finished the trail and hiked back to Hart’s Pass instead of going into Canada. I even saw my friend Max from Kickball. I knew he was hiking the Washington section but didn’t think I’d see him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/The Last Night On TrailPost1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the fire that is burning  on the border. There were signs at the trailhead saying it’s about 10 miles east of the PCT. As long as the wind stays blowing east, we should have a beautiful day tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/The Last Night On TrailPost2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our campsite is in a nice little bowl on top of a ridge. The views around us are great and we’re mostly blocked from the wind. It’s hard to ask for a much better last night on trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/LastNightSunset.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Randall</name></author><summary type="html">The first thing I do when I decide to get up in the morning is open the valve on my air mattress. This forces me to get up. Today, when I pulled in the valve, it came all the way off. Well, at least it lasted me almost exactly one thru-hike. I was able to get the valve back on so it holds air for tonight.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Feels Like Fall</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/10/Feels-Like-Fall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Feels Like Fall" /><published>2017-09-10T20:06:20-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-10T20:06:20-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/10/Feels-Like-Fall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/10/Feels-Like-Fall/">&lt;p&gt;The last highway crossing in Washington is at Rainy Pass. I was hoping for some trail magic, since I haven’t really gotten any in Washington. So when I turned a corner and heard cheering, I knew something was up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Feels Like FallPost0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big group of people had set up camp a little down the trail and were cooking breakfast. They had drinks and chairs and everything a hiker could ever want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we continued climbing. I feel like nobody talked about the climb out of Stehekin ahead of time, but it’s one of the biggest on the trail, if not the biggest. 7700 feet of climbing over 27 miles. It’s gradual, but it’s still a lot of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, it was pretty cold today, making the climb easier. It felt like fall and some of the larches agreed. They’re beginning to change colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Feels Like FallPost1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we climbed, the views got better. When we got over the top, they got incredible. Today was an “easy” day where we only did about 30 miles. Compared to the last few days there was a lot less climbing too. So we took some extra breaks and really tried to enjoy ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Feels Like FallPost2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got lucky that the smoke cleared up here and we were able to see the North Cascades in all their glory. We only have 40 miles to the border.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Randall</name></author><summary type="html">The last highway crossing in Washington is at Rainy Pass. I was hoping for some trail magic, since I haven’t really gotten any in Washington. So when I turned a corner and heard cheering, I knew something was up.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Trail Is Open</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/09/The-Trail-Is-Open/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Trail Is Open" /><published>2017-09-09T20:21:45-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-09T20:21:45-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/09/The-Trail-Is-Open</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/09/The-Trail-Is-Open/">&lt;p&gt;As it gets later in the year, the sunrise gets later and later. I used to wake up at 5 am and have plenty of sunlight. Now it’s dark until 6. So, to make sure I got the first bus to Stehekin I hiked in the dark. Lots of people had the same idea and there was a train of headlamps going down the trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never heard of Stehekin, it’s a weird little town on the North end of Lake Chelan. The only way to get there is by boat, plane, or foot. It has a hotel with a small store, a post office, and the best bakery I’ve ever been to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus makes a stop at the bakery and gives people a chance to get things before heading to the ferry landing and “downtown” of Stehekin. I grabbed a bacon and cheese croissant and some apple pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at Stevens Pass I met a woman named Penny. Her son is hiking the PCT and she came out to support him through Washington. She’s been driving from town to town, meeting him along the way. She was in Stehekin today and so excited to see someone that was hiking with her son. I was pretty far ahead of him, but he has a Garmin Inreach that broadcasts his location every 4 hours. We figured out how far behind he was and when he might make it to town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fun town stop, but a short one. I bought my food for the last 3 days and we had lunch at the lodge. I browsed Facebook a little on some slow and expensive wifi before taking the bus out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/The Trail Is OpenPost0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the trailhead, you could see spawning salmon in the river below. The ranger there said they were Kokanee salmon, which are landlocked chinook apparently. They live in Lake Chelan and go up the river to spawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North Cascades National Park requires permits for camping and only allows camping in designated sites. Since I wasn’t going to be hiking all 16 miles to get out of the park, I would need a permit. I grouped up with Bubba and Lunch and we got a permit for 6 Mile Camp, about 11 miles from the trailhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/The Trail Is OpenPost1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rangers made a big deal about hanging our food, and there’s a bear wire here to hang it from so we all did it. It’s the first time I haven’t slept with my food on the whole PCT. Even in the Sierras when I had a bear can, I still slept with my extra food bag that wouldn’t fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s only 70 miles to the border now and it’s looking like the fire won’t be able to spread to the PCT as fast as we can finish. 3 more days.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Randall</name></author><summary type="html">As it gets later in the year, the sunrise gets later and later. I used to wake up at 5 am and have plenty of sunlight. Now it’s dark until 6. So, to make sure I got the first bus to Stehekin I hiked in the dark. Lots of people had the same idea and there was a train of headlamps going down the trail.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Above The Clouds</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/Above-The-Clouds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Above The Clouds" /><published>2017-09-08T19:50:47-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T19:50:47-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/Above-The-Clouds</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/Above-The-Clouds/">&lt;p&gt;In the middle of the night I felt a tiny splash of water. Then another and another. It was raining! I jumped out of my tent to put the rain fly on and by the time I finished, I’m pretty sure it had stopped raining. In the morning I woke up in a thick fog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day started with a steep climb that took me above the clouds and gave me the best view of Glacier Peak yet. Next it dropped way down to cross the Suiattle River. I guess the trail used to be about 5 miles shorter here until a bridge washed out. They built the new bridge farther downstream in an area that looks like it won’t wash away any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Above The CloudsPost0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bridge is huge, and it’s a surprise seeing it out this far. It’s at least 50 PCT miles in either direction to the nearest town, one of the most remote places on the trail. I met a trail crew today and they said the town of Darrington isn’t too far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the river crossing came a big 4000 foot climb. It would take me away from Glacier Peak and over Suiattle Pass into the North Cascades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Above The CloudsPost1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the day wore on, the fog gave way to sun and clouds. Two of he guys I camped with last. Igor were planning on camping. After about 31 miles. They passed me just before the climb and when I got to that campsite, they weren’t there. It was still early so I cooked dinner and decided what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Above The CloudsPost2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stehekin is about 11 miles away from the trail and the only way into town (other than walking) is the National Park bus. It has a limited schedule so I wanted to be close enough to that I could catch the bus. If I camped, it would be 15 miles into Stehekin, easy enough to catch the 12:30 pm bus. The bus before comes at 9:15, which would be hard to catch with 15 miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still had a couple hours of daylight left so I hiked on. I forded my first river since California (I wanted to wash my feet and didn’t feel like bushwhacking to a log) and arrived at Cedar Camp. It’s not in the national park, but it’s very similar to the campsite where Meghan and I stayed a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Above The CloudsPost3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I had cooked dinner and filtered water already, I actually felt like I got to camp pretty early. It’s a much nicer feeling than last night when I had to hike an extra mile and camp on an abandoned trail that was barely wide enough for my tent.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Randall</name></author><summary type="html">In the middle of the night I felt a tiny splash of water. Then another and another. It was raining! I jumped out of my tent to put the rain fly on and by the time I finished, I’m pretty sure it had stopped raining. In the morning I woke up in a thick fog.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out Of Room</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/07/Out-Of-Room/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out Of Room" /><published>2017-09-07T20:53:29-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-07T20:53:29-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/07/Out-Of-Room</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/07/Out-Of-Room/">&lt;p&gt;On my last day in California I met some southbound hikers that mentioned Mica Lake. Since then I’ve been looking forward to it. It was 30 miles from my campsite and almost 10,000 feet of climbing to get there. So I got going just before 6 to try and make it by a reasonable time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s hike took me into the Glacier Peak Wilderness and around Glacier Peak. I walked through huge glacially carved valleys and descended into thick woods. There was water running all over the place, much of it thick with glacial flour from the grinding glaciers above me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Out Of RoomPost0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many rivers and streams to cross today. Most had bridges, but this was the most interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Out Of RoomPost1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It broke at some point and the water was rushing over the middle when I crossed. Nothing scary, but kinda weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Out Of RoomPost2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After crossing the bridge, I had to climb up and up and up to get over to the next valley, where Mica Lake was. There were some great views of Glacier Peak. It’s way more rugged looking than the other Washington volcanoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/OutOfRoom3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made it to the lake around 6:00 and was planning on cooking dinner and getting a few more miles in. It was pretty cold and windy, so I took some pictures and enjoyed the view before heading on. Even with the haze, it was a beautiful place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got to my planned campsite, Milk Creek, I found that all the sites were taken. It was almost dark and I was exhausted from hiking 35 miles. My guide said there was another site in about a mile where the PCT meets up with an old abandoned trail that used to be the PCT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure why the trail was abandoned but it seems like maybe a bridge washed out and they just connected another trail back to the PCT at a different bridge. I had to go downhill about 100 feet and then uphill a few hundred more, just to get close to the creek I just crossed. It was really frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, that next campsite wasn’t full and it even has a pit toilet.  There are two other guys here who had the same problem I did. At least it makes tomorrow a little easier.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Randall</name></author><summary type="html">On my last day in California I met some southbound hikers that mentioned Mica Lake. Since then I’ve been looking forward to it. It was 30 miles from my campsite and almost 10,000 feet of climbing to get there. So I got going just before 6 to try and make it by a reasonable time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blueberries</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/06/Blueberries/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blueberries" /><published>2017-09-06T20:15:13-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-06T20:15:13-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/06/Blueberries</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/06/Blueberries/">&lt;p&gt;The summer my parents bought our cabin, we discovered the property was covered in wild blueberries. We picked them and ate them and made pies. After that first summer, it never seemed like they came back as plentiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today on the trail, the blueberries were plentiful. It slowed me down because I was stopping to eat them. Normally I don’t like blueberries, but for some reason I love the tiny wild ones. Maybe it’s because it reminds me of that first summer at the cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Stevens Pass doesn’t open until 9 am, I got to sleep in. I didn’t last long and actually found the cot less comfortable than my air mattress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the moms of a hiker staying at the hostel has been following him and supporting him by car for the last week. She was staying at the lodge with us and made her son and his friends some breakfast. Luckily there was some leftovers and I got some pancakes for breakfast. Then she gave us all a ride back to the ski resort. It’s not far, but any non trail mileage is best avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I picked up my food package from Stevens and then headed to their cafe for more breakfast. They had some pre made breakfast burritos so I got one of those. Then I got a chocolate milk. And a Red Bull. And as I was checking out I noticed they had smoothies. So I got one of those too. I drank my drinks and ate breakfast while talking to other hikers and employees of the ski resort. Then it was time to hike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/BlueberriesPost0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s hike took me past another section of the PCT I had done before. This one near Lake Valhalla. The smoke seemed a bit better than previous days but the views still weren’t great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/BlueberriesPost2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed a lot of hikers today. Everyone is slowing down, trying to prolong their hike. I’m speeding up because I’m terrified that a fire near the border is going to close the trail.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Randall</name></author><summary type="html">The summer my parents bought our cabin, we discovered the property was covered in wild blueberries. We picked them and ate them and made pies. After that first summer, it never seemed like they came back as plentiful.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Another Day In Smokey Paradise</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/05/Another-Day-In-Smokey-Paradise/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Another Day In Smokey Paradise" /><published>2017-09-05T21:55:10-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-05T21:55:10-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/05/Another-Day-In-Smokey-Paradise</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/05/Another-Day-In-Smokey-Paradise/">&lt;p&gt;I was hopeful that today would be better. I woke to ash on my tent. It was actually a bit better. It seemed like the smoke combined with water droplets to make more of a fog than a smoke cloud. Still sucked though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Another Day In Smokey ParadisePost0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s cathedral rock. It’s a huge mountain that pushes up out of the middle of the valley. I’ve seen it on a clear day and it’s amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed a lot of alpine lakes today. Deception Lakes was first and it was still really nice, despite the smoke. I ate some food and got water here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Another Day In Smokey ParadisePost1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I came to a part of the PCT I had really been looking forward to. A few years ago I climbed the mountain on the right with my friends Phil and Damon. The view from the top was amazing and the valley is incredible. This time I saw it from the other side where the mountain actually looks quite a bit more imposing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Another Day In Smokey ParadisePost2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t make it to Stevens Pass in time to get any food or drinks so I headed right to the Mountaineers Lodge. It’s a cool old ski lodge that has hostel style lodging. For $20 you can stay a night and take a shower. They don’t have laundry, so I wore my clothes in the shower and hung my stuff up to dry in their ski gear drying room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Another Day In Smokey ParadisePost3.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning I’ll go to the ski resort and get a package full of food for the next few days to Stehekin. Then I’ll hit the trail and hope the smoke clears.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Randall</name></author><summary type="html">I was hopeful that today would be better. I woke to ash on my tent. It was actually a bit better. It seemed like the smoke combined with water droplets to make more of a fog than a smoke cloud. Still sucked though.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Smoke</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/04/Smoke/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smoke" /><published>2017-09-04T21:05:06-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-04T21:05:06-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/04/Smoke</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/04/Smoke/">&lt;p&gt;After a clear night where I saw THREE meteors, I awoke to the familiar smell of wildfire. Sometime in the night the wind shifted directions and filled the alpine lakes wilderness with smoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/SmokePost0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of hiking it looked like I might get out of it. Unfortunately though, the PCT headed mostly east today and took me right back into the smoke. The smoke made the climbs extra difficult and today there were a lot. I did over 9000 feet of climbing. It couldn’t have been good for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed what looked like some cool alpine lakes, but I could barely see them. Then I descended down into a valley and saw this waterfall. I also so Santa’s Helper, who was shuttling people around the Sierra. He gave me a ride up to Kearsarge Pass. I didn’t know he was going to be hiking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/SmokePost1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a break at the waterfall and had some lunch. Then, I stood up, put on my pack, and walked away… without my seat pad. This one made it longer than the last one I guess. I didn’t realize it until I had hiked about 6 miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/SmokePost2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was kind of a bummer with the bad views and bad air. I somehow managed to do 34 miles though. I actually wanted to stop about 5 miles earlier, but the campsites were totally full. No big deal, it’s just 5 more miles. With 1700 feet of climbing! It was brutal but I made it &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; before dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met a girl at camp who was on a laptop. Something I haven’t seen on the trail yet. Then she told me she was heading south, planning on getting all the way to Mexico. I asked about her mileage and she said she was hiking in the mid 30s. Whoa! That’s crazy for just starting. Then she explained how she just finished the Appalachian Trail. That makes more sense. I can’t imagine starting another long trail when I finish but I hope she makes it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was a long and hard day. Luckily I still had the can of beer that Meghan’s dad gave me before leaving Snoqualmie Pass. It was well earned today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Randall</name></author><summary type="html">After a clear night where I saw THREE meteors, I awoke to the familiar smell of wildfire. Sometime in the night the wind shifted directions and filled the alpine lakes wilderness with smoke.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Passing Through</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/03/Passing-Through/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Passing Through" /><published>2017-09-03T19:43:05-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-03T19:43:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/03/Passing-Through</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/03/Passing-Through/">&lt;p&gt;My plan was to meet Meghan at 11 am and I only had about 9 miles to go. I managed to sleep in until 6 today and took my time getting ready. I made it to the pass around 10 and claimed my free beer from Aardvark Express. I also enjoyed a cinnamon roll while I waited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Passing ThroughPost0.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meghan got to the pass at 11 with her parents and her sister showed up with Seth. She brought me some new shoes and food for the next section. We ordered pizza and drank some beer at Dru Bru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After eating all that pizza I had to climb out of the pass. The climb was steep and rocky with hundreds of day hikers. This section went over the Kendall Katwalk, a section of trail that was blasted out of a cliff side. I’ve always heard it was one of the scariest parts of the PCT but it really wasn’t at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the brutal climb, it was about 6 o clock and I decided to make camp at Ridge Lake. There were a handful of other people here, but as cooked dinner by the lake it seemed like dozens showed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Passing ThroughPost1.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are thru hiking but there are lots of weekenders because of Labor Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/Passing ThroughPost2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;photo2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was pretty great having a long break today and seeing Meghan and her family. They’ve been so helpful for my whole hike. I doubt I could have done it without them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Randall</name></author><summary type="html">My plan was to meet Meghan at 11 am and I only had about 9 miles to go. I managed to sleep in until 6 today and took my time getting ready. I made it to the pass around 10 and claimed my free beer from Aardvark Express. I also enjoyed a cinnamon roll while I waited.</summary></entry></feed>